### **Vhanne Brian A. Villaso**

Address: Purok Mangga, Sitio Fatima, Linao, Minglanilla, Cebu 6046

**Phone:** +63 927 626 0964

**E-mail:** vhannebrianvillaso@gmail.com

**LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vhanne-brian-villaso-213690231/

Self-motivated team player with a dedication to learning and honing skills throughout the process. Improving skills as a software engineer is a challenge and chance to grow in this industry. Experienced in Web and Software Development programming languages.

#### **Skills & Interests**

**Software Development:** Java, C#, Python, C++, PHP, Typescript, JavaScript, SQL

Web Development: HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Node.js, ReactJS, Vue, Git and GitHub

Framework: Django REST, .NET, Angular

**Soft Skills:** Time management, Teamwork, Leadership, Adaptability

**Interests:** Artificial Intelligence, Creating Websites, and Software

## **Professional Experience**

# **Sun Asterisk Philippines**

Backend Web Developer Intern

Jul 2022 – Aug 2022

Tech Stack: React & Django

- Designed and developed a Home Inventory System utilizing React for the front-end and Django for the back end.
- Implemented core CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) functionalities to manage inventory items effectively.
- Collaborated on integrating assigned features, ensuring seamless functionality and user experience

# **Confidential Company**

Software Engineer I Jul 2023 – Present

Tech Stack: Java & C++

- Conducted thorough testing and documentation to ensure the quality, functionality, and reliability of software products.
- Designed and implemented new features to enhance the functionality and performance of document solutions products.
- Performed advanced debugging to identify and resolve software issues, ensuring optimal system performance.
- Contributed to patent creation by developing innovative solutions and documenting intellectual property.
- Collaborated with third-party companies to integrate external systems and technologies, ensuring seamless interoperability.
- Delivered tailored customization of products to meet client-specific requirements, enhancing customer satisfaction.

# **Projects**

# **Windows Applications**

**CFPL Interpreter** 

C#

• Built an interpreter cable of parsing and executing basic CFPL Programs (CIT First Programming Language), simulating early learning language environments.

# **Web Applications**

Home Inventory System (Intern Project – Backend Developer) React.js Django REST

> Designed and implemented RESTful APIs for inventory tracking. CRUD operations, secure authentication

TeknoPlat (Frontend Developer)

React.js. Django REST

- Developed responsive UI components for a tech services platform, focusing on clean design and performance
- Integrated frontend logic with backend API endpoints and handled form validation Subscription Monitoring System (Alliance *JumpStart Program Frontend Developer*) *React.js, C#(.NET)* 
  - Built interactive dashboards and subscriptions management views
  - Worked closely with backend engineers to integrate .NET APIs and optimize data flow.

# Teknoy Inquiry Assistant Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Python, NLP

- Created a user-friendly frontend for a chatbot-like web assistant designed to respond to university-related queries in real-time.
- Focused on responsive design and dynamic UI rendering.

# **Education**

**Diploma** Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Cebu Institute of Technology - University - N. Bacalso Ave., Cebu City,

Cebu, Philippines Dean's List 2022-2023

# **Certifications**

• EY GDS Academia ServiceNow Program

• Alliance Jumpstart Program